迷 情 記
新奧爾良 一九五九年
從此他們幸福快樂地生活在一起
女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemen!
Ladies and gentlemen...
我們大家舉杯
I would like to propose a toast...
為邁克爾和伊麗莎白乾杯
to Michael and Elizabeth Courtland...
世界上最後一對浪漫夫妻
this world's last romantics.
十週年婚慶快樂
Happy tenth anniversary!
週年快樂
Happy anniversary!
請允許我特別向一個人致敬
And if you'll allow me, a special toast to this man...
一個擁有無窮野心和精力的人
a man of endless energy and ambition...
南方商業新巨擘
the cream of the new South...
我親愛的朋友 新搭檔
my dear friend and new senior partner...
共同打造新奧爾良未來一流的地產開發項目
in what will soon be the finest real estate development in New Orleans...
旁切地產
the new Pontchartrain Estates!
謝謝 鮑勃
Thank you, Bob.
鮑勃對我一片溢美之詞
Bob has very generously referred to me...
說我是南方新巨擘
as part of the cream of the new South.
這種話我承受不起
I think that might be a little bit genteel for me.
要我形容我自己 我不過是個
I would be more inclined to consider myself more of...
中西部來的邊緣混混而已
oh, skim milk of the Middle West or something.
有力量
Energy...
有雄心
ambition.
我希望
I would hope...
我的這些能力
that we could direct those qualities...
可以用在有用的地方
to try and retain...
建設新的南方
for the new South...
為我們傳統的南方帶來新價值
some of the graceful values of the old South.
- 爸爸 - 怎麼了
- Daddy. - What?
- 跟我跳支舞好嗎 - 我跟你跳舞
- Will you dance with me? - Will I dance with you?
如果我跟你跳舞 你答應我什麼
What will you do if I dance with you?
我答應跟你跳舞啊
I'll dance with you.
讓媽媽一起來 好嗎
Let's bring Mommy in, okay?
- 晚安 - 晚安 約翰
- Good night. - Good night, John.
鮑勃 再次感謝
Bob, thanks again.
謝謝 鮑勃 晚安 黛比
Thank you, Bob. Good night, Debbie.
晚安
Good night.
謝謝你能來
Thank you. It was nice having you.
晚安 卡爾
Good night, Carl.
媽媽 媽媽
Mommy! Mommy!
親愛的
Honey?
不准報警 明天準備好五十萬美元
否則別指望你妻女活著回來
打開
Turn it on.
說話 小孩 該死
Come on, kid. Talk, damn it!
告訴你爸爸 一定要準備錢
Tell your daddy how much you want him to bring that money!
爸爸 請你準備好錢 求求你
Daddy, please bring the money, please!
- 很好 - 求你來救我和媽媽
- That's real good. - Please come get me and Mommy, please!
很好 非常好
That's good. That's real good.
找誰
Yes?
有人送這個東西給考蘭先生
I'm supposed to bring this to Mr. Courtland.
進來吧
Come in.
什麼事 孩子
What is it, son?
- 考蘭先生嗎 - 是我
- Mr. Courtland? - Yeah.
送信的人說你會給我小費
The man said you'd give me a tip.
五塊錢 謝謝
Five dollars! Gee, thanks.
- 他長什麼樣 - 誰
- What did he look like? - Who?
讓你送東西的人
The man who gave you the bag.
普通的人
Just a man.
你慢慢說 再想想
Let's start at the beginning. Slow down.
把五十萬美元裝進手提箱裏
上午十一點搭乘棉花號遊覽船 丟到河邊的老百慕達碼頭
說話 小孩 該死
Come on, kid! Talk, damn it!
告訴你爸爸 一定要把錢準備好
Tell your daddy how much you want him to bring that money!
爸爸 請你準備好錢 求求你
Daddy, please bring the money, please!
求你來救我和媽媽
Please come get me and Mommy, please!
報警
Call the police.
我要把旁切地產的錢撤出來了
I guess I'll have to take my money out of the Pontchartrain project.
我明白 考蘭
I know, Court.
這事我也很難受
Just thinkin' about it makes me sick.
我不會趁火打劫
You know, I'm not gonna take advantage of this.
我們根據你的計劃繼續開發
We're gonna develop the land just as you planned.
要蓋你想蓋的公園
We'll build your park.
我也喜歡樹
Hell, I like trees.
其實你不必執行我的計劃了
If you pick up the option, you're not obligated to do my plan.
現在你可以按你的想法做 你的選擇很多
You can do anything you want with it. You know that.
我開發這個項目是為了你
I want to do this thing for you.
謝謝 鮑勃 真的很感激
Thanks, Bob. I appreciate that.
再說 我們還有一周的時間
Of course, there's still a week on the option.
如果警察把你的錢追回來 一切還能回歸原樣
If the police can get your money back, it'll be just like before.
那要去銀行取錢了
Well, I guess somebody oughta get to the bank.
我親自去
I'll go there myself.
布裏偵探來了 他想馬上見你
Inspector Brie is here. He'd like to see you right now.
- 請他進來吧 - 好的
- Would you send him in? - Okay.
你好 警官 感謝你登門 請坐吧
Hello, Inspector. Thank you for coming out. Sit down.
謝謝
Thank you.
喝杯咖啡嗎
Would you like a cup of coffee?
不用了 謝謝 考蘭先生
No, thank you, Mr. Courtland.
這種事真是折磨人
It's an excruciating situation.
這種感受你更深刻
I guess I don't have to tell you that.
既要做好最壞的打算 但又要抱著希望
Preparing for the worst and hoping for the best.
我見過很多類似的案子
I've seen many cases very similar to this.
最後 人質都能平安回家
They all ended up with the successful return of the hostages...
綁架犯也都被繩之以法
and the apprehension of the kidnappers.
只是要多用腦筋 要夠清醒
It's just a matter of intelligence and calm nerves.
希望你盡量配合我們 相信警方 考蘭先生
Just try to leave this as much as possible to us, Mr. Courtland.
你能幫上的忙其實不多
There's nothing you can really do.
我願意付錢 錢對我不重要
I'm willing to pay the money. The money isn't important.
這正是關鍵 考蘭先生
That's the hell of it, Mr. Courtland.
這些人都是職業綁匪
These men are professionals.
如果他們拿不到錢 他們便會放棄
If they're caught without the loot, they give up.
如果他們把錢拿到了手 我們的勝算就不高了
If they got the money in hand, we may have a very dangerous fight.
真的嗎
Are you sure?
絕對如此
Absolutely.
當然 這最終取決於你
It is, of course, finally your decision.
你會怎麼辦
What would you do?
歡 迎 搭 乘 棉 花 號 游 船
這是我們多次實踐後的結論
Something the lab has developed.
我們前往他們指定的地點
We go through the drop as instructed.
把手提箱裏放上假鈔
False money and a small radio transmitter...
再佈置一台追蹤器
in a locked briefcase.
用無線電追蹤拿錢的人
We track the pickup man by radio truck.
他會帶我們找到人質
He leads us to the hostages.
簡單又安全
Foolproof.
你妻子和女兒的生命絕對不會有危險
At no point will the lives of your wife and daughter be in danger.
交給我們辦好了
Just leave it to us.
把預測情報給我
Give me an estimation.
我拿到了 拿到了
I got it, I got it!
這下你開心了 小姑娘
You oughta be happy, little girl.
你爸爸拿錢給我們了
Your daddy come through with the money.
你們馬上就安全了
And everything's gonna be all right.
媽媽 爸爸拿錢來了
Mommy, Mommy! Daddy brought the money!
這是什麼玩意
What the hell is that?
追蹤器
Transmitter.
混蛋
Son of a bitch!
看看 你爸爸覺得你們就像這些白紙一樣
Look at this. This is what your old man thinks you're worth!
- 毫無價值 - 媽媽
- Nothin'! - Mommy!
我是布裏偵探
This is Detective Brie.
我是新奧爾良警局的布裏警官
This is Detective Brie of the New Orleans police force.
你們被包圍了
The house is surrounded.
舉起手出來投降 我們就不會開槍
Come out with your hands raised and you will not be harmed.
- 我們怎麼辦 - 冷靜點 去拿刀
- What do we do? - Be calm. Get the knife.
別慌張
Don't panic.
把她們的繩子砍斷 我們走
Cut those ropes and let's get outta here.
把窗戶砸開
Break that window open.
媽媽 媽媽
Mommy! Mommy!
不准開槍 否則這小孩死定了
Don't shoot unless you want the kid to get it!
別開槍 別開槍
Hold your fire. Hold your fire.
彼得森 我是布裏
Peterson, this is Brie.
我們在羅塞道 接近大橋
We're on the Broussard Road approaching the bridge.
路障就位了嗎
Are your roadblocks in place?
一切就緒 警官
All set on your side, Inspector.
我正在疏散一部運油車
I'm helping an oil truck off the road over here.
快把車弄走 我們上橋了
Get it out of there! We're on the bridge now!
新奧爾良商人 邁克爾·考蘭的妻子和女兒
The wife and daughter of New Orleans businessman Michael Courtland...
昨天被殺
were killed yesterday...
人質拯救行動失敗
when a kidnap-rescue effort sadly backfired.
這位是負責此案的奧古斯特·布裏警探
Over here is Inspector August Brie, who's in charge of this case.
警官 請你描述一下事情的詳細經過
Inspector, can you tell us exactly what happened here?
很報歉
I'm sorry.
現在我不便透露任何信息
I can't divulge any information at this time.
事情實在太悲慘了 無話可說
It's just been too tragic, that's all.
警方已經盡力了
The police did all they could.
屍體打撈始終沒有進展
The search for the bodies remains fruitless...
汽車爆炸十分強烈
hampered by the explosion of the automobile...
密西西比河的水流也很湍急
and the currents of the Mississippi.
深 切 懷 念
伊麗莎白·考蘭   艾米·考蘭
旁 切 紀 念 公 園
新奧爾良 一九七五年
這是你們的票
Here are your tickets.
記住 你明天十二點半出發
Now, remember, you leave at 12:30 tomorrow.
九點十分到達羅馬 然後換乘快車去佛羅倫薩
You arrive in Rome at 9:10 and you take the Rapido to Florence.
- 護照帶了嗎 - 帶了
- Do you have your passport? - Yeah.
我放到你手提箱裏
I'll put these in your briefcase.
- 你準備好了嗎 邁克爾 - 是的
- You about ready, Michael? - Yeah.
我馬上就好
I won't be a second.
那意大利人叫什麼 達努佐
What's that Italian's name, D'Annunzio?
他好像有點悶
He's a bit of a bore, I'm afraid.
不過很有錢
A rich one, though.
希望他的英語比我的意大利語強
I hope his English is better than my Italian.
我負責跟他套近乎 他很吃馬屁那一套
You let me take care of him. He's very susceptible to flattery.
我會誇他像凱撒一樣英明 像教皇一樣誠懇
He's gonna love it when I tell him he's as wise as Caesar...
他一定樂得屁顛屁顛
and as honest as the pope.
這次旅行一定很開心 鮑勃
You know, I'm gonna like this trip, Bob.
真的 我一直充滿期待
Really, I'm lookin' forward to it.
我終於能體會這些年你在佛羅倫薩參加宴會的感受了
I can find out what you were doing on the Florentine junkets all these years.
有的吃 有錢賺
Food, money...
還有藝術 完美
and above all art, my man.
我是個藝術愛好者
I'm a lover of fine art.
- 這是我唯一的把柄 - 你真是個文藝復興青年
- It's my only vice. - You're just a Renaissance man, Robert.
他說八點
He said 8:00.
謝謝 鮑勃 看來你說得對
Oh, thanks, Bob. You know, I think you're right.
我早就該來意大利了
I should have come back to Italy years ago.
跟你說了 這裏是西方文化的發源地
I told you, old boy. It's the birthplace of western art.
有件事我很迷惑
One thing that puzzles me.
這些老頭的老婆怎麼都這麼年輕
How do these old guys get such young wives?
- 我去問問 - 別去
- I'll ask them. - Don't.
你說得沒錯 想看看我老婆的照片嗎
I think so too. Would you like to see a picture of my wife?
你老婆的照片
Picture of your wife?
給他看看照片
Go ahead, show him a picture.
用美國人的話說就是 極品辣妹
As Americans say, "Such a jewel."
好女人
Wonderful woman.
還會做飯 極品廚師
And cook... such a cook.
她很可愛
She's lovely.
這是瑪麗亞 極品好女人啊
This is Maria. Such a wonderful woman.
- 給我生了六個孩子 - 很可愛
- And I have six children. - She's lovely.
可愛的女人
Lovely lady.
你的疑惑消除了嗎
Aren't you glad you asked?
不可思議的女人
A fantastico woman.
所以我要賺很多錢
That's why I have to make so much money.
她喜歡錢 我也該獎勵她錢
She loves money, and she deserves it.
- 人人都愛錢 - 也愛女人
- Everybody likes money. - And women.
不是每個人都愛錢 先生
Oh, not everybody likes money, signor.
比如我的搭檔 邁克爾
You take my partner here, Michael.
他和我 在新奧爾良郊區
He and I own, in New Orleans...
擁有一片既廣闊又漂亮的地皮
one of the biggest, best plots of land in the suburban city.
買了十五六年了
For 15, 16 years...
他就是不肯在那蓋房子
he has refused to build anything on that land.
就蓋了個墓地
Nothing but a tomb.
各位接著玩 時間有點晚了 恕我失陪
If you gentlemen will excuse me, it's a little late.
什麼 他居然覺得晚了
Late? He thinks it's late.
我還沒跳舞呢
Hell, I haven't even danced yet.
你昨晚不走就好了 考蘭
You should have stayed with us last night, Court.
年輕時光不多了
We aren't getting any younger.
你醒悟啦
Found that out, did you?
你因為昨晚的事生氣嗎
You're not upset about last night, are you?
沒有
No.
那我們今天幹什麼
So what are we gonna do today?
沒想好 不如遊覽一下城裏的風景
I don't know. I thought we might just do a little sightseeing...
多看看藝術品 少喝點酒
absorb a little culture and a little less wine.
好計劃
That sounds great.
嘿 考蘭
Hey, Court.
你和伊麗莎白是在這教堂認識的吧
Isn't this the church where you and Elizabeth met?
我去去就來
I'll be right back.
怎麼樣 考蘭
Well, how was it, Court?
老樣子
The same.
你準備好回美國了嗎 考蘭
Well, you about ready to go back to the old U.S. Of A., Court?
不
No.
我想再多呆幾天
I thought I'd like to stay around a few more days.
是嗎
Oh?
我想再回一趟那間教堂
I'd like to go back to that church again.
為什麼想再回去
Why do you wanna do that?
你能陪我一起去嗎
Will you come with me?
沒問題 如果這能讓你心情好點 我樂意奉陪
Well, okay, if it'd make you feel better.
我的天吶
Oh, my God.
- 你一個人呆在這裏真的沒事嗎 - 沒事
- You sure you're gonna be all right, Court? - Yeah, I'll be fine.
- 我還想再呆幾天 - 好吧
- I just need a few days. - All right.
你好好照顧自己
You take real good care of yourself now.
謝謝 鮑勃
Thanks, Bob.
沒關係 我會說英語
Oh, that's all right. I speak English.
你是美國人嗎
You are American?
你喜歡聖母圖
You like the Madonna?
這是一三二八年畫的
It was painted in 1328...
畫家是柏那多·達迪
by Bernardo Daddi.
是文藝復興早期作品
That's early Renaissance.
- 你是美術學生 - 不是
- You a student? - No.
我以前是個 怎麼說來著
I used to be... what do you call it?
雙語秘書
Bilingual secretary.
後來我聽說這裏重建有困難
Then one day I read about the restoration project...
我就對自己說 桑德拉 聖母需要你
and I said, "Sandra, the Madonna needs you."
於是我辭了那份悶工作就來了
So I quit my dull job, and here I am...
開始學藝術史
an art historian.
這份工作很重要
I can't think of anything more important.
至少 做這份工作 就算跟人閒聊
Well, at least they don't holler and scream at you...
也不會挨上司罵
when you talk to strange men.
你是做什麼的
What do you do?
我是個地產商人
I'm in land development, real estate.
很厲害的工作呢
Ah. Well, that sounds important.
不
No.
一點也不
It's not.
我叫考蘭
My name is Courtland.
邁克爾·考蘭
Michael Courtland.
很高興認識你 我叫桑德拉
Happy to meet you. I'm Sandra.
桑德拉·波蒂拉尼
Sandra Portinari.
你做這份工作很久了嗎
You've been doing this work a long time?
我不負責修復
Oh, I'm not doing the restoration.
我只是打雜的
I'm just a workman.
我負責為專家準備材料
But I prepare everything for the specialist.
是這樣的 幾年前
You see, several years ago...
由於發過洪水
long after the floods...
濕氣滲到聖壇壁畫裏面
moisture seeped into a portion of the altarpiece...
然後就開始剝落
and it began to peel...
顯露出下面的舊壁畫
revealing an older painting underneath.
然後 藝術專家們開始想辦法
Then the art scholars had to decide what to do.
到底是要除掉達迪的名畫
Should they remove and destroy a great painting by Daddi...
揭開下面理藏多年的舊壁畫呢
to uncover what appears to be a crude first draft underneath it?
還是修復達迪的壁畫
Or should they restore the original...
永遠掩藏下面的壁畫呢
but never know for sure what lies beneath it?
你會怎麼辦
What would you do?
靜心等待
Hold on to it.
美是需要保護的
Beauty should be protected.
非常好 專家也是這麼決定的
Good. That is what the scholars decided to do.
我剛才算是免費給你做了次演講
Now you have a free lecture, and you don't have to read the brochure.
我可不可以
I wondered if I might...
請你吃頓晚飯
repay you for your lecture...
就算是為這次演講還情
and ask you to dinner somewhere.
你不明白
You don't understand.
在我們這 吃晚飯的意義可大了
Dinner can be a pretty serious affair here.
午飯呢 附近有家餐廳
Lunch. I know a place nearby.
先生 我以為通常都是意大利男人追美國女人來著
Signor, I thought it was the Italian men who picked up the American women.
好吧 吃午飯
All right. Lunch.
不過我還要再干一個半小時的活
But I have to work another hour and a half before I go.
我等你
I'll wait.
你以前來過佛羅倫薩嗎
So you were in Florence before?
很久以前了
A long time ago.
戰後 我被分派到這裏
I was stationed near here after the war.
當時我還沒出生 不過我媽媽
I wasn't even born, but my mother often told me...
經常說起戰爭有多麼悲慘
how hard times were then.
你跟媽媽住在一起
You live with your mother?
現在不了 我在維琪奧港租了公寓
Not anymore. I have an apartment near Ponte Vecchio.
媽媽獨自把我撫養成人
But I was raised by my mother.
我父親很早就拋棄了我們
My father deserted us a long time ago.
真悲傷
That's sad.
美國佔領期間佛羅倫薩什麼樣
What was Florence like during the Occupation?
很混亂
Confused.
這個話題實在不該問我
I'm really not an expert on the Occupation.
我當時注意力不在這
My mind is elsewhere.
我在這認識了我妻子
I met my wife there.
話題越來越深刻
Oh, the plot thickens.
咱們坐在這訴苦
Let us sit and tell sad tales...
一個父親的棄女 一個喪妻的鰓夫
about deserted daughters and lonely husbands.
難怪你到教堂的時候
I thought you had a familiar melancholy look...
臉上帶著一種悲傷的情緒
when you came into the church.
其實不是
No. That wasn't...
她去世很久了
She died a long time ago.
抱歉 我並無惡意
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
主要是 我這種單身女子
It's just that a single girl...
遇到過很多遊客 多數是美國男人
meets a lot of men, mostly Americans...
一個個都想跟我談他們的老婆
who want to tell her about their wives.
我的戒心就比較重
It's not very flattering.
她是什麼樣的人
What was she like?
伊麗莎白
Elizabeth...
她很像你
She was very much like you.
像我
Like me?
她是意大利人
She was Italian?
不是 她長得很像你
No, she looked very much like you.
你帶她的照片了嗎
Do you have a picture of her?
沒有
No.
我真得走了
I really have to go now.
改天還能見面嗎
May I see you again sometime?
行
Sure.
我們可以吃頓不重要的晚飯
We could have a nonserious dinner.
- 真的 - 什麼時候
- Seriously. - When?
- 今晚 - 今晚
- Tonight. - Tonight?
可以嗎
Is that all right?
那只有五個小時了
That's only five hours from now.
足夠你換衣服了
Plenty of time to change.
好吧 不過我下班後要去醫院看我母親
All right, but I have to go see my mother at the hospital after work.
我去醫院等你
I'll meet you there.
醫院在聖喬萬尼
Oh, it's the San Giovanni.
我知道
I know.
好吧
All right.
拜拜 再見
See you. Ciao.
再見
Ciao.
你很喜歡那間餐館 是嗎
You're very fond of that restaurant, aren't you?
是的
Yeah.
你在那裏認識了伊麗莎白
That's where you met Elizabeth.
不是 我們是在你工作的教堂認識的
No, we met in the church where you're working.
不過我們常去那裏吃飯
We used to eat in the restaurant though.
跟我講講她吧
Tell me about her.
- 伊麗莎白 - 對
- Elizabeth? - Yes.
我剛才說了 她很像你
Well, as I said before, she's very much like you.
她長得真的很像你
I mean, she looked very much like you.
頭髮是棕色的
She had brown hair...
留得很長 跟你髮型不一樣
and wore it longer, kind of different, you know.
她喜歡擦粉紅色唇膏
And she wore pink lipstick.
從來不擦胭脂
And she never wore rouge.
她走路
Oh, her walk...
她走路的方式跟你完全不同
Her walk was 180 degrees different than yours.
- 是嗎 - 對
- Different? - Yeah.
- 她走路是典型的布林莫爾式 - 布林莫爾式
- She had a very Bryn Mawr walk. - Bryn Mawr?
對 布林莫爾式
Yeah, very Bryn Mawr.
什麼是布林莫爾式
What do you mean, "Bryn Mawr"?
就是那種 布林莫爾
Bryn Mawr? That's kind of a walk.
怎麼說呢
It's... Well, it's...
就是 我也不知道
It's... I don't...
你往前走 上台階
Just walk, and I'll... Just go ahead and walk upstairs.
不 你這是意大利式
No, that's an Italian walk.
那是當然
What do you expect?
你走路很好看 但不是布林莫爾式
It's a good walk, but it's just not a Bryn Mawr walk.
布林莫爾式 走起路來好像滑步 滑著走
A Bryn Mawr walk is a kind of a glide, you know?
就是那種舊時打扮的女孩 穿著很長的雨衣外套
Those girls used to wear long polo coats in those old days, long raincoats.
滑步走 好像上課遲到了一樣
They kind of glide, like they're late for class.
走得太快 像滑行起來一樣
They move fast and just kinda glide.
你再試試 滑步 我指導你
This time now, just glide. I'll talk you through it, okay?
- 好吧 - 不要闊步走 滑行
- All right. - Don't sashay so much. Just glide.
- 好的 - 去吧
- All right. - Go ahead.
滑步
Just glide.
不是模特步 滑著走
No, not like a model. Just glide.
對 就這樣
That's it. That's it.
噢 邁克爾
Oh, Michael.
她喜歡叫我邁克
She called me Mike.
邁克
Mike?
對了 我是個正統的天主教女子
Listen, I am a good Catholic girl.
教皇的話我全都聽
I obey everything the pope says.
明白嗎
You know?
教皇同意我明天見你嗎
What would the pope say if I saw you tomorrow?
我還要上班呢
You forget I have a job to do.
明天晚上
Tomorrow night.
再過兩天吧 好嗎
Let's wait a couple of days, all right?
星期六我放假 我有空
Saturday. I'm free all day Saturday.
- 幾點 - 十一點
- What time? - Oh, 11:00?
我在這等你
I'll be here.
好吧
All right.
拜
Bye.
晚安
Good night.
桑德拉
Sandra.
再往右一些
Move to your right.
很好 再近一點 近點
All right, come closer now. Come closer.
再近一點
A little closer.
你念的什麼 意大利帥哥給你寫的求愛十四行詩嗎
What is that, a love sonnet from an Italian boyfriend?
不是 你吃醋了
No, it isn't. Jealous.
但丁寫的
That's Dante.
有生之年
"While life endures...
不要對你愛的女子不忠
you should not ever be inconstant to your lady...
寧死不說謊
who in death doth lie.
說出我的心聲 我內心的一聲長嘆
So speaks my heart and afterwards doth sigh."
你知道嗎 小時候
You know, as a child...
我經常到教堂來
I used to go to the church...
但丁偷看比阿特麗斯的地方
where Dante came to watch Beatrice.
比阿特麗斯就坐在這裏
Beatrice, la bella donna, would sit here...
坐在爸爸旁邊
with her father...
那邊
and there...
你過來
Come here.
- 你站這 - 我是爸爸
- Over there. - I'm her father.
- 不是 - 不是嗎
- No. - No?
是二十三歲的年輕但丁
The young Dante, 23 years old...
站在這裏看著比阿特麗斯
would stand and watch Beatrice.
這裏呢
And here...
中間這裏
in between...
坐著伴遊的女子
sat the Lady of the Screen...
但丁假裝喜歡她
a lady Dante pretended to love...
這是為了不讓比阿特麗斯害羞
so that Beatrice would not be embarrassed...
被他火熱的凝視羞紅臉
by his continual gaze.
你還愛著伊麗莎白 是嗎
You still love Elizabeth, don't you?
所以你才喜歡我
That's why you want me.
她怎麼死的
How did she die?
我殺了她
I killed her.
對不起 我要去醫院了
I'm sorry, but I must go to the hospital right away.
- 我母親病得很重 - 我跟你一起去
- My mother's very ill. - I'll go with you.
- 不用了 我自己去 - 請讓我去
- It's not your problem. I go alone. - Please.
好吧 我們快點
All right. Well, let's hurry then.
媽媽
Mama.
你靠近一點
Come closer.
我看不清你
I can't see you.
你愛我的桑德拉嗎
You love my Sandra?
噢 媽媽
Oh, Mama.
一定要告訴我
I must know now.
很好
Good.
你愛他嗎
You love him?
我不知道
I don't know.
他要娶你
He marry you.
不好意思 我媽媽就這樣 最愛說媒
You'll have to forgive my mother. She's always been a matchmaker.
你有錢嗎
You rich?
你是黑幫嗎
You gangster?
不是
No.
嫁給他
You marry him.
媽媽 我倆剛認識
Mama, we hardly know each other.
以後有的是時間
You get to know him...
先結婚後戀愛
after you're married.
深 切 懷 念 慈 母
瑪麗亞·弗吉尼亞·波蒂拉尼
我也不敢相信 但他就是這麼寫的
No matter how many times I read it, it still says the same thing.
你自己看
Look at that.
幫我定下五月二號 聖路易大教堂
"Hold St. Louis Cathedral for May 2.
準備好香檳酒
Break out the champagne.
我在十九號星期二回來 並到教堂結婚
I'm returning Tuesday the 19th for a church weddin'.
愛你的 邁克爾
Love, Michael."
可憐的考蘭
Poor Court.
腦子都糊塗了
He's a goner now.
不過說真的 珍妮
I tell you, Jane.
要不是親眼看見 我也不敢相信
If I hadn't seen it with my own eyes, I wouldn't have believed it.
那女孩簡直是伊麗莎白轉世
It was like Elizabeth had stepped out of her tomb.
過幾天你就能親眼看見了
Yeah, well, you'll see soon enough for yourself.
- 你覺得她是不是圖他的錢 - 我哪知道
- Do you think she's a gold digger? - I don't know what to think.
要不要問問艾爾曼醫生
Maybe we should call Dr. Ellman.
- 問他什麼 - 他一直是考蘭的醫生
- What good would he do? - He's been treating Court for years.
但是艾爾曼活在一九七五年
But Ellman lives in 1975.
而邁克爾則活在一九五九年
Michael lives in 1959.
- 邁克爾先生 - 朱迪
- Mr. Michael! - Judy.
見到你真好
Good to see you too.
這位是桑德拉
I want you to meet Sandra.
桑德拉 這位是朱迪 我們家的永久成員
Sandra, this is Judy, a lifelong member of this house.
你好 桑德拉小姐
Hello, Miss Sandra.
邁克爾先生寫信說起過你
Mr. Michael wrote me about you.
- 我來幫你拿 - 謝謝
- Let me help you with this. - Thank you.
房子真漂亮
It's beautiful here.
佛羅倫薩的達努佐先生那單生意 相當有戲
Now, this D'Annunzio-Florence deal is lookin' awful good, Court.
那老孤貍總算計劃給咱們投資一大筆錢了
Looks like the old goat is finally gonna invest some big money with us.
現在我要做一些基礎工作
Now, I've got a preliminary breakdown here...
要為工程項目開發 做費用和現金流預估
of the basic estimated development cost and cash flow...
還有合併意向書
for the joint venture proposal.
請你親自審一審
I'd like you to look those over if you would.
嘿 鮑勃
Hey, Robert.
要是我建議你先放一放
You wouldn't file an in personam suit against me...
你不會一氣之下去告我吧
if I asked you to table all this for a while, would ya?
我就要結婚了 好多事要忙 我現在沒那個精力
I mean, with the wedding plans and everything, I'm just not up to it.
- 能不能等等 - 沒問題 考蘭
- Would you mind, for a while? - Can do, Court.
搭檔就是要為你分憂
Can do. That's what a partner's for, I guess.
朋友們都很期待見見桑德拉
Well, our friends are certainly looking forward to meetin' Sandra.
他們都會在大日子見到她
They'll all meet her on the big day.
結婚的大日子
Big day of the big wedding.
我新生活的開始
Big day of my new life.
用意大利語怎麼說來著
How do you say in Italian?
我的重生
"La vita nuova."
聽著 考蘭
Look, Court...
我知道這不關我的事
I know this is none of my business...
可是你不覺得有點太快了嗎
but don't you think maybe this is all a little hasty?
有點不成熟
A little premature?
你說得對 這不關你的事
You're right. It's none of your business.
朱迪
Judy.
什麼事 桑德拉小姐
Yes, Miss Sandra?
樓上有個房間鎖住了
There's a locked room upstairs.
是什麼房間
What is it?
以前是主人的臥室
It was the master bedroom.
為什麼上鎖
Why is it locked?
我也不知道 桑德拉小姐 我很久沒打掃過它了
I don't know, Miss Sandra. I don't clean it anymore.
我想看看 你能幫我打開嗎
I want to see it. Can you open it for me?
鑰匙不在我這 邁克爾先生拿著
I don't have the key. Mr. Michael keeps it.
在哪裏
Where?
告訴你也沒關係 他放在抽屜裏
Well, I guess it's all right. He keeps it in his desk.
一九五二年二月十四日
"February 14, 1952.
佛羅倫薩的日子
I think the days in Florence...
是我一生中最快樂的時光
will be the happiest I will ever have.
新奧爾良很不錯
New Orleans is a nice town...
邁克對我很好
and Mike is very good to me...
可是 一切都不同了
but it is all so different now.
他每天都忙著工作
He is busy at work all day...
有時候我不禁懷疑 邁克是不是愛生意超過了我
and sometimes I wonder if Mike loves me as much as his business."
就是這 親愛的
There it is, darling.
漂亮嗎
Isn't it beautiful?
等到了十九號
And on the 19th...
這裏就完全屬於我們
it'll be all ours.
好大啊
It's so big.
邁克 兩百位客人太多了吧
And Mike, 200 guests. That's a lot of people.
辦個小小的儀式就行了
Just a small ceremony would be fine.
不行 這不僅是一個儀式
No, it's more than a ceremony.
我要辦成慶典
It's a celebration...
應該有成千上萬人
and there should be thousands...
我希望一切都要
and everything's got to be...
非常特別
very special.
好吧 聽你的
Yes. If you say so.
早上好 羅伯特
Good morning, Robert.
- 早上好 邁克爾 - 早上好 珍妮 雪莉
- Good morning, Michael. - Good morning, Jane, Shirley.
你好 考蘭
Hello, Court.
你怎麼來了 醫生
What are you doing here, Doc?
我只能這樣才能找到你
This was the only way I had to get in touch with you.
你這個人不好找啊
You're a hard man to get a hold of.
有什麼事嗎
What can I do for you?
我想找你坐坐 聊聊家常
I thought we might just sit down for a while and have a personal talk.
純粹是來看朋友的
Purely a social visit.
你是心理醫生 卻一點都不會撒謊
Why is it psychiatrists are such lousy liars?
鮑勃 珍妮
Robert, Jane.
你們進來一下 好嗎
Would you come in here, please?
是你們請艾爾曼先生來的嗎
Did you all ask Dr. Ellman up here?
他打電話問你在哪裏
He called to find out how you were.
我們覺得你應該找人談談
We thought you might wanna be talkin' to somebody.
好吧 謝謝
That's fine. Thank you.
邁克爾 為什麼你不跟查理談談
Michael, why don't you talk to Charlie?
- 行了 - 這是為了你好
- That's fine. - It's for your own good.
我昨天去府上見了桑德拉 你不會介意吧
I went by and saw Sandra yesterday. I didn't think you'd mind.
你覺得我不會介意
You didn't think I'd mind?
你侵犯了我的隱私 還問我介不介意
You invade my privacy and you ask if I'd mind?
你先聽聽你說的話 好好聽一聽
Will you listen to yourself? Stop and listen to what you're saying.
- 你知道你在幹什麼嗎 - 我很清楚
- Can't you see what you're doing? - I know exactly what I'm doing.
我不希望別人侵犯我的私生活
I don't want anybody interfering with my private life.
別忘了 我非常瞭解你
You're talking with somebody who already knows you...
可能比所有人都瞭解你
knows you better probably than anybody else.
昨天 桑德拉和我談了很多事
Sandra and I talked about a lot of things yesterday.
我覺得你對她不公平
I don't think you're being fair with her.
你不該處於內疚才娶她
You shouldn't marry out of a sense of guilt...
不該由於對伊麗莎白的病態思念而娶她
or out of some morbid preoccupation with Elizabeth.
如今 桑德拉對伊麗莎白揮之不去
And now Sandra is obsessed with the idea of Elizabeth.
她昨天一直在問伊麗莎白的事
That's all she wanted to know about yesterday.
她陷入了你的幻想中 你該清醒一點
She's caught up in your fantasy. You must know what's happening.
給自己一些時間
Give yourself some time.
先跟桑德拉培養一下感情
Let your relationship with Sandra grow first.
希望你能繼續治療 即便不請我 請別的醫生也行
And I want you back in therapy. If not with me, with some other doctor.
一定要多給自己一些時間
But give yourself some time.
說得對
Right.
不過你都誤會了
Except you got it wrong.
我吃完午飯
We'll talk about it...
就找她談
after lunch.
那好 你都想開了
Good. We'll work everything out.
有時間到我辦公室來談談
Just come on down to my office and...
我不希望你太衝動 將來後悔
I just don't want you to do anything impulsively that you'll regret.
再見
Bye-bye.
發生什麼事了
What's happening?
邁克
Mike?
- 你為什麼在家 - 因為你在家啊
- Why are you home? - Because you're here.
因為我的心在家
Because my heart's here.
我再也不想離開家了
Because I never want to leave.
喂 考蘭
Hello? Court?
你去哪了 我們好擔心
Where are you? We've been so worried.
這件事我們都很抱歉
Look, we're both really sorry about that.
我們不是故意的 我們以為你
We didn't mean it. We only thought you...
好 他在這 你等等
Okay, he's here. Just a minute.
邁克爾
It's Michael.
邁克爾老兄 你在哪
Michael, old boy, where are ya?
你不覺得這太
Well, now, don't you think it's...
別這麼急 邁克爾
Now, don't be hasty. Michael.
好吧 既然你這麼堅持
Okay, if that's what you want.
考蘭
Court?
他想把他在公司的股份轉成信託基金
He wants us to put his share of the company into a trust fund.
- 文件已經寄出來了 - 他在哪
- He's already sent the papers. - Where is he?
誰知道
Who knows?
- 明天 - 什麼
- Tomorrow. - What?
我們明天結婚吧
Let's get married tomorrow.
我們請太平紳士到這裏為我們主持婚禮
We can have the justice of the peace perform the ceremony right here.
- 為什麼要明天 - 我不想等了
- Why tomorrow? - I don't wanna wait.
不是到聖路易教堂嗎 和你朋友們一起
What about St. Louis Cathedral and all your friends?
那邊可以取消 再說 我根本沒有朋友
We can have it cancelled. Besides, I don't have any friends.
我今天才醒悟 你覺得失望嗎
I found that out today. Would you be disappointed?
不 一點也不
Well, no, not at all.
借由路易斯安那州政府
And now, in accordance with the powers invested in me...
賦予我的權力
by the state of Louisiana...
我宣佈你們結為夫妻
I now pronounce you man and wife.
我等了好久
I've waited so long.
現在
Now...
我是你妻子了
I am your wife.
我是伊麗莎白
I am Elizabeth.
為了一個原因 我回來了 邁克
I came back for one reason, Mike.
我回來了
I came...
再給你一次機會 證明你的愛
to give you a second chance to prove your love.
我永遠都愛你
I've always loved you.
不要再離開我
Never leave me alone.
我要永遠和你在一起
I want to be with you always.
永遠
Always.
我現在好幸福
I am happy now.
伊麗莎白
Elizabeth.
現在 我是你妻子了
Now, I am your wife.
我是伊麗莎白
I am Elizabeth.
我回來了 再給你一次機會
I came to give you a second chance.
桑德拉
Sandra!
不准報警 明天準備好五十萬美元
否則別指望你妻女活著回來
把五十萬美元裝進手提箱裏
上午十一點搭乘棉花號遊覽船
丟到河邊的老百慕達碼頭
這麼早打擾你 很抱歉 有急事
I'm sorry to call you so early. Something's come up.
趕快跟我去銀行 我們得取五十萬美元
You've gotta go to the bank with me now. We've gotta get $500,000.
- 別問了 - 你在說什麼
- Don't ask me... - What are you talking about?
- 車上再跟你說 - 要這麼多錢幹什麼
- I'll tell you part in the car. Okay? - What's this money gonna be used for?
什麼名義 我是借貨還是送給你
What's your collateral? Am I loaning, investing or just giving it to you?
這是我的第二次機會 你不明白
It's a second chance for me. You don't understand, but...
- 先進來再說吧 - 不 我不想進去
- Don't you wanna come inside? - No, I don't wanna come inside!
- 你現在很緊張 - 我知道
- You're under incredible strain. - I know I am!
- 找艾爾曼醫生談談 - 去他的吧 快走吧
- You should talk to Dr. Ellman. - The hell with Dr. Ellman! Please hurry.
- 為什麼要去銀行 - 我需要五十萬美元
- Why do you want to go to the bank? - I wanna get $500,000.
- 你沒那麼多現金 - 我還是有些錢的
- You don't have that kind of cash. - I've got some money.
- 你沒看公司的帳嗎 - 我還有地
- Have you seen our books lately? - We've got land.
還有旁切那塊地產 和其他的資產項目
We've got the Pontchartrain property. We've got other property.
- 把你那一半賣給我行嗎 - 什麼都給你
- And you wanna give me half? - I'll give you anything!
只是暫時的 快走吧
It's only for a short while. Please come.
既然這樣 那好 我們去簽署文件
If that's what you want, I'll do it. We'll get the papers, and you sign.
- 你發瘋我不奉陪 - 隨便
- You can act crazy, I don't have to. - Anything!
我把那塊地買過來 好好保護 公司得靠我照顧
I'll take that land to protect it from you. I gotta look after the company.
- 好 我去車上等你 - 我去穿衣服
- All right! I'll wait in the car. - I'll just get dressed.
你得簽署這些文件
You're gonna have to sign these papers. Court.
簽這裏
Right there.
考蘭老兄
Old Court.
就是弄不到錢
Just can't come up with the money...
沒給伊麗莎白 也沒給你
not for Elizabeth and not for you.
媽媽
Mommy.
媽媽 媽媽
Mommy. Mommy.
媽媽
Mommy.
看看 你爸爸覺得你們就像這些白紙一樣
Look at this. This is what your old man thinks you're worth.
毫無價值 毫無價值 毫無價值
Nothing! Nothing! Nothing!
媽媽 媽媽
Mommy! Mommy!
把她們的繩子砍斷 我們走 把窗戶砸開
Cut those ropes and let's leave. Break that window open!
不准開槍 否則這小孩死定了
Don't shoot unless you want the kid to get it!
你爸爸覺得你一文不值啊
It looks like your daddy doesn't think you're worth a dime.
你鮑勃叔叔也許願意出點錢
I'm sure your Uncle Bob will.
媽媽
Mommy.
國 際 機 場
我不要 一分錢也不要
I don't want this. I don't want any part of it.
五十萬美元 很難拒絕啊 親愛的
$50,000 is a lot of money to turn down, darling.
- 你賺的 歸你了 - 本來不該這樣的
- You keep it. You earned it. - It wasn't supposed to be like this.
從一開始你就知道 這是骯髒的勾當
It was a dirty business from the start and you knew it.
跟你說了 考蘭要麼放棄那塊地
I told you Court would either give up the land...
要麼精神失常 沒法經營
or be declared mentally incompetent to manage it.
你同意了的 現在良心發現有什麼用
And you agreed. So don't start getting an attack of conscience now.
至少你幫他振作起來了
At least you kept him out of bed. Look at it that way.
你明不明白我犯了多大的錯
Do you realize what I've done?
我要回去找他 向他坦白一切
I wanna go back to him. I wanna confess everything.
求他原諒我
I wanna beg him to forgive me.
你冷靜點 桑德拉
Look. You hold on. Sandra.
先好好想一想
Just keep your head a minute.
我們剛騙了他幾十萬
We just swindled a man out of millions.
你要是跟邁克爾坦白了
Now, the law isn't exactly gonna look lightly on that...
法律可不會原諒你
if you go back to Michael and confess.
你跟我策劃的圈套天衣無縫
You made a dirty deal with me and you executed it flawlessly.
你是我最成功的一筆投資
You're the best investment I ever made.
你表演的伊麗莎白 把老考蘭騙得神魂顛倒
Old Court fell for your Elizabeth act hook, line and sinker.
享受一下這筆罪惡的財富吧
So now I think you're entitled to the due wages of sin.
你不明白
You don't understand!
我現在怎麼辦
What am I gonna do now?
這種問題有點晚了 親愛的
It's a little late for existential questions, darling.
拿著錢走吧 錢能幫你忘掉一切憂愁
You just take the money. Believe you me, it'll help you to forget.
我該怎麼辦
What am I gonna do?
- 我不能拿 - 快走
- I can't take it. - Come on!
快走
Look! Move!
快點
Hurry up!
你拿到錢了嗎
Have you got the money?
- 這不夠 - 這是給你的
- This isn't enough. - It's all for you.
其他人呢
What about the others?
- 他們都死了 - 天啊
- They're all dead. - Christ!
這次行動本應完美無缺的
Smart business deal this turned out to be.
考蘭真讓人驚訝
Courtland surprised all of us!
拿著錢趕緊走吧
So just take the money and get out of here!
鮑勃叔叔
Uncle Bob.
媽媽在哪裏
Where's Mommy?
她死了 親愛的
She's dead, honey.
你爸爸沒給錢
Your daddy didn't pay the men...
他們殺了她
and they killed her.
你看 我給他們錢了
You see. I gave the man the money.
以後我來照顧你
I'm taking care of you now.
現在 你跟他走
Now, you're gonna go with him...
坐飛機遠走高飛 我有朋友照顧你
on the plane to a faraway place where I've got friends you can live with.
一個禮拜之後我過去看你
Now, I'll be there in about a week to see if everything's okay.
爸爸在哪裏
But where's Daddy?
他不要你了 親愛的
He don't want you anymore, honey.
你跟他走
Now you go with the man.
- 去吧 - 不
- Go on! - No!
- 跟他走 - 鮑勃叔叔 不
- Go with him! - Uncle Bob, no!
跟他走吧
Go with the man!
鮑勃叔叔
Uncle Bob!
爸爸 我不會請求你的原諒
Father, I do not ask forgiveness.
我知道你無法原諒
I know there can be none.
我沒有跟媽媽一起被殺
I was never killed with Mother.
鮑勃付了贖金 把我送到佛羅倫薩
I was ransomed by La Salle and brought to Florence...
跟波蒂拉尼太太住在一起
where I lived with Mrs. Portinari.
他們從小教育我 是你殺了我媽媽
I was raised believing you killed Mother.
我恨你 我生活的唯一目的 是為媽媽報仇
I hated you. I lived for the day when I could revenge her.
然後鮑勃來找我 讓我幫他從你手中騙那塊地
Then La Salle came to me with his plan to swindle the land from you...
我抓住了這個機會
and I got my chance.
但你不像他說的那樣
But you were not like he said.
我從沒想到
I never thought I would...
會愛上你
love you.
女士們先生們 很抱歉打擾大家
Ladies and gentlemen, we are sorry to disturb you at this time...
飛機遇到了強烈的氣流
but we have just encountered some unexpected turbulence.
請大家馬上返回座位
Would you please return to your seats immediately and...
請開門
Excuse me.
箱子裏沒有錢
It wasn't there. The money wasn't there.
錢不見了
It wasn't there.
考蘭
Court.
你把我叫起床
You got me out of bed...
逼我給了你五十萬美元
forced me to give you $500,000.
當時你簡直發瘋了
You were actin' crazy.
裏面當然沒有錢 我要保護你
Of course the money wasn't there. I had to protect it from you.
真錢在我這
I have the real money.
我是為你好
I was only lookin' after your own good.
錢都是你的了
It's all yours now.
我不能看著你把錢扔掉
And this will surely keep you from throwin' it away.
我殺了她
I killed her.
她回來了 給我第二次機會
She came back a second time...
讓我證明我的愛
to let me prove I loved her...
我卻殺了她
and I killed her.
現在她走了
Now she's gone.
你就是留不住女人 是不是
You just can't seem to keep a woman, can you?
你這個自以為是的混蛋
You self-righteous son of a bitch!
你以為你是誰
What did you think you were anyway?
隨心所欲地支配人
Steppin' on anybody you wanted to...
什麼事都要你說了算
tellin' people what to do and when to do it.
你倒坐得安穩
Sittin' on your ass...
那麼多錢從指縫裏溜走
while a fortune slipped through our fingers!
我們本來可以發大財
Do you know how rich we could have been?
你真是不在乎錢啊
But you don't care about money, do ya?
你從來不在乎
You never did.
為了一個撒謊的賤人 今天你又扔了幾十萬美元
You just threw away millions this mornin' for that lyin' little bitch.
殺了我吧
Go ahead and kill me!
連她也要殺
You gonna kill her too?
她跟我是一夥的 傻子
She was in it with me, you fool!
從一開始就是
She was in it from the start.
她回羅馬了
She's goin' to Rome...
拿著你的五十萬美元
with $50,000 of yours.
你不僅扔掉了很多錢
You didn't just throw away a fortune.
也拋棄了你的生活
You just threw away your whole life.
飛往倫敦的七零二號航班
TWA flight 702 to London...
預計十點半起飛
scheduled for departure at 10:30.
旅客朋友請到十六號登機口登機
Passengers now boarding at gate 16.
去羅馬的下一班機是幾點鐘
When's the next flight to Rome?
羅馬 明晚八點
Rome... Tomorrow evening, 8:00 p.m.
你要定票嗎
You wanna make a reservation?
對
Yeah.
頭等艙還是商務艙 先生
Would that be first class or coach, sir?
頭等艙
First class.
稍等一下
Excuse me a minute.
喂 對
Hello. Yeah.
好的
All right.
先生 你真幸運
Sir, you are in luck.
今晚八點去羅馬的班機返航了
Our 8:00 flight from Rome has just returned...
引擎故障要檢修
to check out an engine malfunction.
現在 問題已經解決了
Now, the problem appears to be cleared up...
今晚十一點在三十六號門重新起飛
and the flight is rescheduled to take off at 11:00 p.m. From gate 36.
我幫你修改一下
If you want me to fix this for you...
爸爸
Daddy!
你帶錢來了
You came with the money!
爸爸
Daddy!
艾米
Amy?
爸爸
Daddy.
爸爸 爸爸
Daddy. Daddy.
Daddy.Daddy.
劇 終